Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic is an expert in storytelling with data.
تُعد Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic خبيرة في سرد القصص مع البيانات.
In her book, Storytelling with Data,
ففي كتابها، Storytelling with Data،
she lays out six lessons for communicating with data.
تقدم ستة دروس للتواصل مع البيانات.
First, understand the context of your visualization.
أولاً، فهم سياق مرئياتكم.
Second, choose the appropriate visual display.
ثانيًا، اختيار العرض المرئي المناسب.
We saw the most common visualizations in the last lesson.
لقد رأينا المرئيات الأكثر شيوعًا في الدرس الأخير.
Third, eliminate the clutter.
الثالثة، القضاء على فوضى.
Remove parts of the visual that take away from the points you're trying to make.
إزالة الأجزاء من المرئيات التي تستبعد النقاط التي تحاول توضيحها من خلال المرئيات.
Fourth, focus the attention where you want it.
رابعًا، تركيز الانتباه على الموضع الذي تريده.
Highlight the parts of the feature that you want your audience to notice and act upon.
حدد أجزاء الميزة التي تريد أن يلاحظها جمهورك وتصرف بناءً عليها.
Fifth, think like a designer.
خامسا ، التفكير كمصمم.
This is the hardest aspect for me,
هذا هو الجانب الأصعب بالنسبة لي،
but we will see more of those details in this lesson.
لكننا سنرى المزيد من هذه التفاصيل في هذا الدرس.
And finally, tell a story.
وأخيرًا، سرد قصة.
The visuals you display to others should provide a story that moves the viewer to act.
يجب أن تقدم العناصر المرئية التي تعرضها للآخرين قصة تحفز المشاهد على الفعل.
In the previous lesson,
في الدرس السابق،
you learned about the displays that can be used with different data types.
تعلمتم عن العروض التي يمكن استخدامها مع أنواع مختلفة من البيانات.
In this lesson, we want to focus on these final components to
في هذا الدرس، نرغب في التركيز على هذه المكونات النهائية
help you best display your data and best convey your message.
لمساعدتك على عرض بياناتك بشكل أفضل ونقل رسالتك بشكل أفضل.